Guide to the Linda Mary Montano Papers, 1931-2014 MSS.386
Fales Library and Special Collections
- OVERSIZE Series I: Art Practice, 267723
  - OVERSIZE Subseries F: Photos, 267725
    - Chicken Photograph, undated; 271269 (Box 73, Folder 5)
    - Dandelion Photograph, undated; 271270 (Box 73, Folder 6)
    - Linda Photograph by Mitchell, undated; 271496 (Box 81)
    - Linda Portrait by Paul, undated; 271330 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - "Montano Oliveros" Photo, undated; 271518 (Folder 13)
    - Performance Photos: "Rosita" by Barbara Spohr, 1980, 1985; 271271 (Box 73, Folder 7)
    - Performance Portraits by Ana Barrado, 1991; 271273 (Box 73, Folder 8)
    - Personal Photos - Oversize, undated; 271274 (Box 73, Folder 9)
    - Untitled Performance Photo Series, undated; 271275 (Box 73, Folder 10)
    - Untitled Performance Photos, undated; 271276 (Box 73, Folder 11, Box 85, Folder 26)
  - OVERSIZE Subseries G: Artworks, 267726
    - 7 Outfits for "Chakra Girl", 1999; 271333 (Box 76, Folder 6)
    - 7 Years of Living Art / 7 Chakras Polaroid Collage, undated; 271331 (Box 76, Folder 7)
    - Aluminum Plate for Art in Everyday Life Cover, undated; 271332 (Box 76, Folder 8)
    - "Angst", undated; 271277 (Box 73, Folder 12)
    - "Beggary Again", 1965, undated; 271278 (Box 73, Folder 13)
    - Chakras: 7 Years of Living Art Transparent Drawings, undated; 271334 (Box 76, Folder 9)
    - Collage Scrapbook, undated; 271500 (Box 82)
    - "Dear Buyer of Hannah Wilke Sculpture..." Tit Print, undated; 271279 (Box 73, Folder 14)
    - "The Call", undated; 271280 (Box 73, Folder 15)
    - Chicken Photographs [1 of 2], undated; 272379 (Box 85, Folder 24)
    - Chicken Photographs [2 of 2], undated; 272380 (Box 85, Folder 25)
    - Chicken Sketches, August 1968; 271281 (Box 73, Folder 16)
    - "December 20, 30 Pigeons, 9:30 AM" Drawings [1 of 2], 1969, undated; 271282 (Box 73, Folder 17)
    - "December 20, 30 Pigeons, 9:30 AM" Drawings [2 of 2], 1969, undated; 271283 (Box 73, Folder 18)
    - "Encounter!", April 1965; 271284 (Box 73, Folder 19)
    - Extra Shoe Drawings [1 of 4], undated; 271335 (Box 76, Folder 10)
    - Extra Shoe Drawings [2 of 4], undated; 271336 (Box 76, Folder 11)
    - Extra Shoe Drawings [3 of 4], undated; 271337 (Box 76, Folder 12)
    - Extra Shoe Drawings [4 of 4], undated; 271338 (Box 76, Folder 13)
    - Figure Sketches [pencil, pen, watercolor], undated; 271285 (Box 73, Folder 20)
    - "Flower Time", undated; 271286 (Box 73, Folder 21)
    - "Forest Time" or "Verdunt I", 1965, undated; 271287 (Box 73, Folder 22)
    - House Drawing, undated; 271288 (Box 73, Folder 23)
    - "I Have Tried To Give My Love To You...", undated; 271339 (Box 76, Folder 14)
    - Landscape Watercolors, undated; 271289 (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Linda Self Portrait, undated; 271497 (Box 81)
    - Occupy Wall Street Sign: "Compassion is the New Currency" Performance at St. Patricks NYC, undated; 272381 (Box 85, Folder 23)
    - Oil Painting Portrait #1, undated; 271501 (Box 82)
    - Oil Painting Portrait #2, undated; 271502 (Box 82)
    - Oil Painting Portrait #3, undated; 271503 (Box 82)
    - Oil Painting Portrait #4, undated; 271504 (Box 82)
    - Oil Painting Portrait #5, undated; 271505 (Box 82)
    - Oil Painting Portrait #6, undated; 271506 (Box 82)
    - Oil Painting Portrait #7, undated; 271507 (Box 82)
    - Oil Painting Portrait #8, undated; 271508 (Box 82)
    - Plastic Chicken Print, undated; 271340 (Box 76, Folder 15)
    - "Play Life", undated; 271290 (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Religious Sketches, undated; 271291 (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Shoe Series: "Camera Shoe", undated; 271347 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Shoe Series: "Cat Shoe", undated; 271348 (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - Shoe Series: "Chicken Shoe", undated; 271349 (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - Shoe Series: "Feather Shoe", undated; 271350 (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Shoe Series: "Feather Shoe", undated; 271512 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Shoe Series: "Feminist Shoe, or S.C.U.M.", undated; 271351 (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Shoe Series: "Flat Shoe", undated; 271352 (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Shoe Series: "Floating Girl Shoe", undated; 271353 (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - Shoe Series: "Girl Shoe", undated; 271354 (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - Shoe Series: "Girl Shoe", undated; 271355 (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Shoe Series: "House Shoe", undated; 271356 (Box 77, Folder 11)
    - Shoe Series: "Men-Women Cork-Cloth Shoe", undated; 271357 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Shoe Series: "Piano Shoe", undated; 271358 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Shoe Series: "Pigeon Shoe", undated; 271359 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Shoe Series: "Red Charger Shoe", undated; 271360 (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Shoe Series: "Sad Shoe", undated; 271361 (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Shoe Series: "Sling Back Wood Heel Shoe", undated; 271362 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Shoe Series: "Toe Open Shoe", undated; 271363 (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - Shoe Series: Untitled Shoe #1, undated; 271364 (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Shoe Series: Untitled Shoe #2, undated; 271365 (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - Shoe Series: Untitled Shoe #3, undated; 271367 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Shoe Series: Untitled Shoe #4, undated; 271368 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Shoe Series: Untitled Shoe #5, undated; 271369 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Shoe Series: Untitled Shoe #6, undated; 271370 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Shoe Series: Untitled Shoe #7, undated; 271371 (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Shoe Series: Untitled Shoe #8, undated; 271372 (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Shoe Series: Untitled Shoe #9, undated; 271513 (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Shoe Series: "Wing Shoe", undated; 271373 (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - "Tongue to Flowers" Linda by Mitchell, undated; 271292 (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Untitled [ink], undated; 271293 (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Untitled [Bird Paintings], undated; 271294 (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Untitled [Flower Painting], undated; 271295 (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Untitled [Green Painting], undated; 271296 (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Untitled [Hand Painting], undated; 271297 (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - Untitled Pastel Work [Child Portrait], undated; 271341 (Box 76, Folder 16)
    - Untitled [People Paintings], undated; 271298 (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - Untitled [Sun], undated; 271299 (Box 74, Folder 11)
    - Untitled [Sunset Painting], undated; 271300 (Box 74, Folder 12)
    - Untitled [Sunset Painting], undated; 271301 (Box 74, Folder 13)
    - Untitled [Watercolor], undated; 271302 (Box 74, Folder 14)
    - Untitled Works, undated; 271303 (Box 74, Folder 15)
    - Watercolor Portraits, undated; 271304 (Box 74, Folder 16)
- OVERSIZE Series II: Inspirational People and Collaborators, 267888
  - Annie Sprinkle: 7 Chakra Poster, undated; 271342 (Box 76, Folder 17)
  - Annie Sprinkle California Tit Print, 2004; 271305 (Box 74, Folder 17)
  - Annie Sprinkle Chakras Target Practice Painting, undated; 271516 (Folder 15)
  - Annie Sprinkle Health/Sex Worker Poster, [2002]; 271306 (Box 74, Folder 18)
  - Annie Sprinkle: Linda Montano Character Portraits [1 of 2], undated; 272377 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Annie Sprinkle: Linda Montano Character Portraits [2 of 2], undated; 272378 (Box 85, Folder 2)
  - Annie Sprinkle Linda Montano Polaroid Collage, undated; 271307 (Box 74, Folder 19)
  - Annie Sprinkle: Linda Montano Portraits, undated; 271308 (Box 74, Folder 20)
  - Annie Sprinkle Performance Photos of Linda, [March 1991]; 271309 (Box 74, Folder 21)
  - Annie Sprinkle Photo: Linda Montano as Guru, undated; 271310 (Box 74, Folder 22)
  - Annie Sprinkle Playing Cards and Earth Manifesto, undated; 271343 (Box 76, Folder 18)
  - Love Art Laboratory: Annie Sprinkle Wedding Invitations [1 of 2], 2003-2010; 271311 (Box 74, Folder 23)
  - Love Art Laboratory: Annie Sprinkle Wedding Invitations [2 of 2], 2003-2010; 271312 (Box 74, Folder 24)
  - Dr. Mehta: Chakra Posters, undated; 271313 (Box 75, Folder 1)
  - Dr. Mehta: "The Collected Words and Advice of Dr. Aruna Mehta", 1990-2000; 271314 (Box 75, Folder 2)
  - Mitchell Payne and Ken Graves: "American Snapshots" Poster, undated; 271344 (Box 76, Folder 19)
  - Mitchell Payne Oversize Self-Portrait Photography, undated; 271315 (Box 75, Folder 4)
  - Mitchell Payne Photographs, undated; 271345 (Box 76, Folder 20)
  - Pauline Oliveros: Sonic Meditations, March-November 1971; 271492 (Box 81)
  - Linda Montano and Tehching Hsieh Art Life: One Year Performance, 1983-1984; 271316 (Box 75, Folder 5)
  - Tehching Hsieh: One Year Performances Promotional Material, 1980-1999; 271346 (Box 76, Folder 21)
  - Tehching Hsieh: One Year Performance Silkscreen Print, undated; 277460 (Folder 10)
- OVERSIZE Series III: Correspondence, 268902
  - Letter to Linda with Melon Seed Rosary, undated; 271495 (Box 81)
  - Oversize Correspondence, 1987, 1999, 2012; 271317 (Box 75, Folder 6)
- OVERSIZE Series IV: Teaching, 268903
  - Student Work: Promotional Posters, undated; 271318 (Box 75, Folder 7)
- OVERSIZE Series V: Family and Juvenilia, 268827
  - Dad Art Diploma, 1931, 2007; 271319 (Box 75, Folder 8)
  - Dad Art: Henry Montano X-Rays, 1999; 271320 (Box 75, Folder 9)
  - Dad Art: Oversize Graduation Photo, 1927; 271321 (Box 75, Folder 10)
  - Henry J. Montano St. Mary's Diploma, June 26, 1927; 271493 (Box 81)
  - High School Reunion Photos, 2010; 271322 (Box 75, Folder 11)
  - Lena Becker Kelly Scrapbook, 271509 (Box 84)
    from Linda Montano: "My grandmother Lena Kelly Lena Becker Kelly made this. Died mid-'60s. I went to her house every day and watched her work (art) in silence. She was my mentor. I looked at this book of hers often."
  - Mildred Kelly Diploma, undated; 271494 (Box 81)
  - Mildred M. Montano Yearbook Photo, 1933; 271323 (Box 75, Folder 12)
  - Montano Family Photograph Album, undated; 271510 (Box 84)
  - Montano Family Photos, undated; 271324 (Box 75, Folder 13)
- Linda Mary Montano Archived Website, February 2016- May 2017; Montano, Linda, 1942-; 2 websites in 2 archived websites. (Box Electronic records, E-records https://wayback.archive-it.org/7078/*/http://www.lindamontano.com/)
  Appraisal
  Robots.txt (a piece of code that prevents crawlers from advancing through a site) were ignored during capture with the permission of the site owner.
  There were six videos included on Linda Montano's website that were not present on the hard drive associated with this collection. These were crawled separately to ensure adequate capture.
  Linda Montano's blog (http://lindamarymontano.blogspot.com) was also crawled separately to ensure adequate capture.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.lindamontano.com and http://lindamarymontano.blogspot.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Feminism and art.; Women artists.; Performance art -- New York (State) -- New York.; Performance artists -- New York (State) -- New York.